狗娘养...
Son of a--
第四季 第三集
S04E03: Open House
我不会走的
I'm not leaving.
沃尔特  我是不会走的
Walt, I'm not leaving.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我能听见你的手机铃声
I can hear your cell phone ringing!
真是莫名其妙
This is ridiculous. I can't--
你怎么了
Uh, what is going on with you?
我给你留了23条语音信息
I've left you, like, 23 messages.
然后呢
And?
我得跟你谈谈洗车店的事
We need to talk about the car wash.
斯凯勒  我现在没时间谈这个事
You know, Skyler, now is not a good time for me, okay?
咱们改日吧
Can we talk about this later?
不行  不改日
No, okay? We can't.
你为什么...
Why are you do--
我的天
Oh, Jesus.
出什么事了
What happened?
没事  撞了一下而已
Nothing. I just bumped it. That's all.
好吧  我必须进屋去
Okay, I'm-- I'm coming in.
说说  到底是怎么回事
Okay, exactly what happened?
情况很复杂  我也不想讨论这事
It's complicated, and I don't wish to discuss it.
不用你操心
It's none of your concern.
你有危险吗
Are you in danger?
沃尔特  你看着我的眼睛
Walt, I need you to look me in the eye
马上告诉我  你有危险吗
and tell me right now, are you in danger?
这样吧
You know what?
就说我现在要操心的事情
Let's just say that I have a hell of a lot more
非常多
on my mind right now
顾不上谈论洗车场的事情
than thinking about buying a d--- car wash.
好吧
Okay.
所以  你能别烦我吗...
So if you could just please...
好吧  那我们去找警察
Okay. Then we go to the police.
什么
What?
都招了吧
We tell them everything--
你是一名毒贩  担心自己的生命安全
that you're a drug dealer afraid for your safety,
以及你家人的安全
and the safety of your family.
还有  你需要帮助
...and you need help.
你有选择的余地吗  沃尔特
What choice is there, Walt?
选择余地
What choice?
如果你有危险
If you're in danger--
那就绝对应该...
...then it would be absolutely--
停吧  停吧
Stop, stop, stop.
你一直在说我"有危险"
You keep saying that word "Danger"--
-"危险"  -但你刚才说...
- Danger. - But you just said--
不  我从没用过这个词
No, and I have never used that word.
我说情况很复杂
I said things were complicated,
然后你就失态了
and then you flew off the handle.
对  那还不是因为看你伤成这样
Yeah, I flew off the handle when I saw that, okay?
你是怎么受的伤
Where'd that come from? Hmm?
洗澡时摔倒了吗
A fall in the shower?
知道吗  你太过偏激了
Uh, this is just so passive-aggressive, you know? I--
太过偏激
Passive-aggressive? Are y--
我就两天
I go two days
没给你回电话  就两天
without returning your phone calls, two days,
就出了一点小插曲
and I have one minor little incident,
然后你就告诉我
and now you're telling me to--
我应该去找警察自首  天呐
I should turn myself in to the police, for God's sake.
-小插曲  -对
- A minor little incident? - Yes.
什么小插曲
What minor little incident?
我跟一个同事起了争执
I had an argument with a co-worker.
好吧
Okay?
然后呢
And?
我们起了争执
I had an argument.
当时在酒吧里
We were in this bar,
我们正在讨论
and we were discussing
一个特别的商务策略
a particular business strategy,
争论过于激烈  无法控制
and it got heated and out of control,
然后他就打了我  就一下
and he hit me-- once.
我没有还击  因为他比我岁数还大
And I didn't retaliate because he's a much older man.
仅此而已
And that's it.
你和人在酒吧打架
You were in a bar fight?
对  斯凯勒
Yes, Skyler,
我和人在酒吧打架
I was in a bar fight.
那你没事吧
So you're okay?
真没事
Really?
对  我没事
Yes. I'm okay.
我觉得  到最后
And I think in the end
这其实是一件好事
it may have been a good thing, actually,
因为我们就可以冰释前嫌了
because we were able to clear the air
就是  互相尊重
and, you know, mutual respect.
所以
So--
冷冻青豆
Frozen peas.
什么
What?
消肿效果最好
It's the best thing for the swelling.
其实没怎么肿
Oh, it's not really swollen.
只是...
It's--
没有青豆
No peas.
你连冰都没有
You don't even have ice.
我去买点青豆  还有冰
I will get peas. I will get ice.
青豆和冰  我记下来了
Peas and ice. I'm writing it down.
我要你...
I need you to...
向我保证
promise me that
-如果你有危险的话...  -斯凯勒
- if things do get dangerous... - Skyler.
答应我
promise me.
没问题
Absolutely.
那么...
So--
洗车场的事
car wash.
亲爱的  约翰
Honey. John.
你好  有什么问题需要帮助吗
Hi, there. Can I answer any questions?
有
Yes.
能给我单独介绍这房子吗
Any chance of a top-off?
我们应该能帮上吗
Oh, I think we can help you out there.
你感觉如何
So what do you think?
很漂亮  很宽敞
Oh. Very nice. Very open.
同感  很敞亮
Oh. I agree. It flows.
充足的日光照射
A whole lot of natural light.
我叫迈克尔・凯尔本
Uh, Michael Kilbourne.
我叫托瑞・科斯特尔
Tori Costner.
很高兴见到你
It's nice to meet you.
三个卧室  两个洗手间其中一个能洗澡
Well, three bedrooms, one and a half baths,
建筑面积两千平米
on just under half an acre.
后边还有一个独立的小屋
That's a non-attached casita out in back,
可以作为办公室或者会客厅
permit usable as office or guest suite.
实木地板
Plank wood floors.
中央空调
Central heat and air.
你已经结婚了吧
I see you're married.
不  离了  刚离不久
No. Divorced, Very recent.
恶习难改
Old habits.
对不起
Oh. I'm sorry.
有孩子吗
Any children?
有  是个小男孩
Yes. As a matter of fact, a little boy.
多大了
Oh. How old?
五月份满四岁
Uh, he turned 4 in May.
双子座  肯定会喜欢后院的
He's a Gemini. Would love this yard.
足够搭一座儿童爬梯
Oh, well, plenty of space for a jungle gym,
附近的幼儿园也很棒
and the neighborhood preschool is fantastic.
我还是想在家教艾利
Oh, well, I think Eli is going to be home-schooled.
那也很好
Oh, well, great.
不是因为什么宗教因素
Not for religious reasons or anything.
我只是想让他得到足够的重视
I just want to make sure that he's getting enough attention.
他还是会去参加夏令营之类的
He'll still go to summer camp and whatnot,
和孩子们一起玩
you know, play dates.
我可不想让他不合群
I don't want him to be socially awkward.
当然  非常理解
Oh, no. Makes a lot of sense.
他考分非常高
He tests very highly--
优于96%的孩子
96 percentile--
但是右脑和左脑
but that whole right brain, left brain--
也得要平衡才行
you want those in balance.
你说小屋里铺有管道  对吗
You said the casita has plumbing?
我出去会踩到泥
I will go out with clay,
所以需要自来水冲洗
so I need access to running water.
那水管是为小型卫生间配备的
Well, it's pipe fitted for a quarter bath,
做工作室再合适不过了
so make a perfect studio.
这行得通
This could work.
是医生的主意
H---, that's the doctor's plan
让她的病人得到放松
to get her patients at ease,
你懂的
if you know what I mean.
可是  护士  我可不是
But, nurse, I'm not one--
我回来了
Hello! I'm back!
汉克
Hank?
在呢
Yeah.
我跑了三家不同的商店
I had to go to three different places
去找你喜欢的润肤霜
to get the moisturizer that you like,
还是买到了
but I got that,
还买了你要的啤酒和薯片
and I got your Shiner Bock and your chips,
还忍不住买下了
and I couldn't resist.
《梦幻足球》的全攻略
The Complete Encyclopedia to Fantasy Football.
上面列了所有近期排名
Look, it has all the latest rankings.
玛丽  我说的是奇多斯薯片  不是炸多斯
Marie, I said Chee-tos, not Fritos.
什么
W-Wait. Uh--
我一直说的是奇多斯
I must have said Chee-tos, like, ten times.
你想要我给你写下来吗
You need me to write it down for you?
不用  我也不想你这么挑剔  你这暴脾气
No, and I don't need you to be mean about it, either, Mr. Grumpy.
我只是说说而已
Well, I'm just saying, you know.
我说的是奇多斯  奇奇奇
I said Chee-tos. Ch-Ch-Ch sound,
实在不可能会听成炸多斯吧
virtually impossible to confuse Chee-tos with Fritos,
在我看来
it seems to me.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
回商店
Uh, back to the store, I guess.
给
Here.
选拔赛还有两个月呢
And the draft's not for two months,
这排名毫无用处
so this is useless.
难以置信
Can you believe it?
什么
What?
什么  这玩意儿
What? This.
你过去也总觉得这地方会被窃听
Well, you always thought this place could be bugged.
现在有答案了
Now we know.
是啊  可我不喜欢
Yeah, well, I don't like it.
这有碍工作
It's a violation of the work space.
我想是吧
Yeah, I guess.
想做点什么吗
Want to do something?
做什么  比如
Do something? Like what?
开卡丁车
Go-karts?
卡丁车  什么
Go-karts? What--
体育馆那边有跑道
Yeah, there's a track down by the Coliseum.
挺好玩的
It's pretty fun.
不了
No.
其实  我
Actually, I have--
我要去见人
I have a meeting, so--
好吧  无所谓
All right. Whatever.
改天吧
Rain check?
当然了
Yeah, Sure.
你近来如何
How you doing?
挺好的
Good.
是吗
Yeah?
你还好吗
You okay?
有什么要跟我聊的吗
Is there, uh, anything we should talk about?
你的眼睛怎样了
How's your eye?
没事
Yeah, it's fine.
有什么要聊聊的吗
Anything we should talk about?
无论如何
For what it's worth...
替你把那废人给铲除了
getting the shit kicked out of you...
不是说你已经适应了  但是
not to say you, uh, you get used to it, but...
你确实有点适应了
you do kind of get used to it.
四个字  美甲沙龙
Two words-- nail salon.
洗钱再合适不过了
It's perfect for money laundering.
这个行业  现金流充足
It's a high volume cash-preferred business
雇佣的是正经员工
with a discreet work force.
我是说  不需要她们保什么密
I mean, nobody does "Mister, me know nothing"
比莫卡佳阿波夫人和她手下妞们好过多了
better than Mrs. Mookjaiaporn and her gals.
古德曼先生
Mr. Goodman--
请叫我索尔
Saul, please. Now,
对这店里的女主人
for the lady of the house--
请给点掌声
drum roll, please--
可以终生享受
how about a lifetime supply
法式光疗甲和去角质服务
of French manicures and enzyme peels?
没错  来吧  犒劳自己下
Ah, yeah. Go ahead, pinch yourself.
古德曼先生  我们不打算买美甲沙龙
We're not buying a nail salon, Mr. Goodman.
我们要买洗车店
We're getting the car wash.
抱歉  我是不是听岔了
I'm sorry. Am I missing something here?
你不是已经试过了吗
I mean, didn't you already try that?
没错  沃特告诉我
Yeah. I mean, Walt told me
你跑去找那个博格丹
that you, uh, took a run at this Bogdan character,
他根本无心跟你讨价还价
and he wrestled you into submission with his eyebrows.
要价一千万美元  对吗
10 million, that was the asking price, right?
显然他有提高到两千万了
Apparently, he upped it to 20.
这交涉得可真好
Ha ho! Nice negotiating.
你谈崩了  这很正常
Yeah. I-- Hey, you bombed. It happens.
打电话给我就对了
You were smart to call me.
现在  你们就退居幕后  放轻松
Now-- Uh, you just sit back, relax,
让专业人士来接管
and let a professional take over.
是谁
Who is that?
来找我的  抱歉
That's for me. Excuse me.
你想干什么  我在谈正事
What do you want? I'm in a meeting.
你之前怎么没想到
Why didn't you think of that before?
这不是我...
It's not my--
我谈正事呢
I'm in a meeting.
修尔可以借用下厕所吗
Can Huell use your bathroom?
修尔是谁
Huell?
当然  上楼就是
Uh, sure. The top of the stairs.
他很快的
He'll be quick.
是胃不舒服
It's a stomach thing.
我们说到哪儿了
So where were we?
专业
Professionalism.
对了  这人要是不想卖  就不会卖的
Yeah. Um, so the guy won't sell, he won't sell.
我可不干
I don't accept that.
他不卖  我可不干
I don't accept that he won't sell.
我想他是缺乏足够的
I-- I think he just lacks the proper...
动机
motivation.
Motivation. Oh. Uh,
是说我们常说的"动机"吗
as in "Motivation" motivation?
我就是确认下  我们说的是一码事
I mean, just so we're on the same page here.
你是说我们开一个他无法拒绝的价钱吗
You're saying we make him an offer he can't refuse?
那可就太戏剧性了  不行
Nothing so dramatic as that, no.
动机
Motivation.
转变态度
Attitude adjustment.
你这妻子太精明了
This one, she's a keeper.
查账可以构成动机
Well, an audit can be highly motivating.
我有个朋友是管税收的
I know a gal over at Tax and Revenue.
让她拿着博格丹的账本查上10分钟
You give her ten minutes on this Bogdan fella's books,
保证让他大难临头
she'll have his sky raining frogs.
不行  这事不能引起税务部门注意
No, we don't want to draw any unwanted tax attention.
不然博格丹卖给我们之后他们还会查
We don't want them looking at us after Bogdan sells.
好吧  非法移民突查怎么样
All right. How about an I.C.E. raid?
他厂里一定有非法劳工
You know he's got illegals working over there.
不可能没有
I mean, he just has to.
我们不想连累无辜的穷苦人  不行
We are not getting a bunch of poor innocent people in trouble, no.
对  而且这些工人你们接管以后也要用
Yeah. And also, you're going to need them after you take over. Tck.
那恐怖主义如何
Hey. How about terrorism?
"胡佛探员  我跟你说"
"Oh, Agent Hoover, I got to tell you,
"最近那家洗车厂"
"I've seen some real Islamic comings and goings
"总有伊斯兰人来来去去"
over there at the car wash."
对  缠着头巾的男人开着货车
Yeah, I mean guys in turbans pulling up in vans
诸如此类的
and stuff like that. Ha ha!
索尔  博格丹是罗马尼亚人
Saul, Bogdan is Romanian.
好吧  不过是随便说说
Okay, well, we're... we're just spitballing here, so...
行  这招总可以
Okay, there's always...
"你这地方不错"
"You got a real nice place here.
"出什么事的话就太可惜了"
A shame if something happened to it."
这个角度
That angle.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
用暴力手段吗
Violence?
调整态度
Attitude adjustment.
不行  这可不行
Oh, no. That? No.
我说的绝对不是这个意思
That is not at all what I meant.
我...我们不做那种事
I... We do not do that.
我们不是那种人  对不对
That's not who we are, right?
对  不行  不行
Yeah. No. No.
她说的对
No, she... she's right.
你们看  这么明显的事还用我说吗
Look, do I need to state the obvious?
这片的洗车厂肯定不下十几家
I mean, there's got to be dozens of car washes in this area.
谁说非要这一家了
Who says it has to be this one?
我说的
I do.
我说非这家不可
I say it has to.
为什么
Why?
我就要这家
I just do.
天...
G....
这倒说明问题了
Well, that clears things up.
我不喜欢那个人  博格丹
I don't like him... Bogdan.
他跟我甩脸色  对你无礼
He was condescending to me, rude about you,
我不喜欢他
and I do not like him.
就这么简单
Simple as that.
我最欣赏爱憎分明的女人了
Hey, nobody appreciates a passionate woman more than I do,
可是  在我们这行
but, uh, in this business,
沃尔特可以帮我作证
and Walt can back me up on this,
最最要紧的就是
the number 1 rule is...
不要感情用事
don't take things personally.
你刚才说...对我无礼是什么意思
What do you... What do you mean, rude about me?
他话里话外说你...
Something along the lines of...
不够个男人  不敢自己去见他
you weren't man enough to face him yourself.
什么
What?
说你让你女人替你做生意
That you had to send your woman to do your business for you.
好吧  身为你们的律师
Okay, uh, speaking as your lawyer,
我得把这话说在前面
I'm going to go on record
这不是个好主意
and say this is a bad idea.
我建议你们不要...
Now, I advise against...
就要这家了
It's this one.
好吧  那...
Okay. So, uh...
我们要做的就是  想出一种非暴力的
all we have to do is think of a nonviolent,
不会引起怀疑的方法  买下洗车厂
unsuspicious way to purchase the car wash
还要...  不伤及无辜
that... that... that protects the innocent
又不能花费2千万美元
and doesn't cost $20 million.
你们一个一个说
Don't everybody speak at once.
你好
Hi.
有什么我可以帮忙解答的吗
Can I answer any questions?
好多勺
Oh. Spoons.
没错  这家主人热爱收藏
Yes. The owner is quite the collector.
是不是很独特
Aren't they something?
50个州的都有
One for each of the 50 states.
事实上波多黎各不能算州
Uh, Puerto Rico is technically a territory.
说不定他们觉得...
You know, maybe they were thinking...
没准儿呢
some day.
没有地下室是吗
Uh, so no basement.
抱歉  没有地下室
No basement. Sorry.
这是个问题  我弟弟是维和部队的
That's a problem. My brother's in the Peace Corps,
18个月之后才回来
and won't be back for 18 months,
我答应帮他保存家具
and I said I'd hang on to his furniture.
如果你需要储物空间
Well, if you're looking for storage space,
这里的阁楼很宽敞
there's an attic area that's sizeable.
阁楼更好
Oh. Huh. Well, an attic might be even better,
只要干燥就行
as long as it's dry.
-我带你去看看  -好
- Let's take a tour. - Okay.
其实呢  这边有宣传单
Actually, I have a handout for you.
信息上面都有
It has all the information.
我是斯蒂芬妮・多斯威尔
I'm Stephanie Doswell, by the way.
我叫夏洛克・布拉特纳
Charlotte Blattner.
很高兴认识你  夏洛特
So nice to meet you, Charlotte.
我也一样
You, too.
我就给他下了最后通牒
So I just told him point-blank...
"你是我丈夫  我爱你"
"You're my husband, and I love you.
"可是你已经53岁了"
"But you're 53 years old.
"这工作压力太大  太辛苦"
"This job has just gotten too stressful
"你该辞职了"
and difficult, and it's time to quit.
然后奇迹发生了  他听了我的
And, miracle of miracles, he listened.
他一定是对工作非常着迷
Still, what a fascinating career that must have been for him.
的确是
It was. I mean,
宇航局就像我们的第二个家
NASA was like a second family to us,
可是  你也知道
but, you know,
该开始新的旅程了
it was time for a new adventure,
靠着他的养老金
so, between his pension
和我做手模赚的钱
and the income I bring in from hand modeling,
我们过得比较富足
we're, you know, comfortable.
地板是重铺的吗
Uh, when were these floors redone?
两年前
Two years ago,
灶台是全新的
and the counters are brand new.
看得出来  洞石
I can tell. Travertine.
很好
Hmm. Nice.
有孩子吗
Any children?
没有
No.
我不太想要孩子
I don't really want kids.
我是不是不该有这种想法
Is that horrible for me to say, do you think?
没有啦  不是所有人都得生小孩的
Not at all. Not everyone has to have children.
你该去跟我丈夫谈谈
Hmm. You should talk to my husband.
这是垃圾处理机吗
Uh, garbage disposal?
瞧瞧这个
Check it out.
不错哦
Score, yo.
我非常喜欢你们家
I really love your home.
谢谢你  米米
Well, thank you, Mimi.
有一种欧洲风情
It has a... very European feel.
是吗
You think?
我在伦敦住过几年
Oh, I lived in London for years,
是的  感觉很熟悉
so yeah, this feels familiar.
伦敦什么地方
Where in London?
60年代我在厄普伍德驻守
I was stationed at Upwood in the '60s.
市中心
Right downtown.
可是我们通常都不在那里
But we were almost never there.
我丈夫是插画师  所以我们经常旅行
My husband is an illustrator, so we traveled a lot...
巴黎  意大利  丹麦
Paris, Italy, Denmark.
那都是在孩子上学以前的事了
it was before the kids were in school,
整理下行李就能到处走
so it was easy to pick up and go.
那时候我的小女儿  露西
That was before my youngest, Lucy,
还未被诊断出患有心内膜炎
was diagnosed with endocarditis.
可怜的孩子
Oh, my.
老天  那是不是
Gosh, is that, uh--
是心脏瓣膜发生了细菌感染
It's a bacterial infection of the heart valves.
那  确实会...
It's-- Yeah, it can be--
真遗憾
Mmm. That's terrible.
她现在还好吗
Is she all right?
你的女儿
Your daughter.
她现在身体可好
Is she okay?
还好  多谢关心
Yes. Th-Thank you.
医生给她装了人工瓣膜
Um, the doctor's put her on a prosthetic valve,
所以她...  露西挺好的
so she's-- Lucy's fine.
能跑能走  还能骑马
Running and walking, riding horses.
谢天谢地
Well, thank goodness.
是啊  我们很幸运
Yeah. We're...very lucky.
请留步  小姐
Excuse me. Miss?
房子不错  多谢
Very nice. Thank you!
我报警了
I just called the police.
好的
Okay, then.
我知道你偷了那把勺子
I know you stole that spoon.
什么勺子  你说什么呢
What spoon? What are you talking about?
你是个小偷
You're a thief.
-你再说一遍  -还是个谎话精
- Excuse me? - And a liar,
乱编故事  你是有什么问题吗
making stories up about yourself. What's wrong with you?
拜托  你才哪里不对劲吧  女士
No. What's the matter with you, lady?
你最好给我闪开
You better just back off, okay?
我丈夫是毒品管制局的探员
My husband is a DEA agent.
我还以为他是名宇航员或是插画家呢
I thought he was an astronaut or an illustrator.
你最好能够自圆其说
You better get your crazy lies straight.
听好了  肥婆
You know what, fatty?
你该庆幸我有约在身  没工夫跟你耗
You are so lucky that I am late for an appointment.
你哪儿都别想去
You're not going anywhere.
放开我的包
Let go of my purse.
-放手  -等警察来了再说
- Let go! - Not until the police get here.
放手  你给我放手
Let go of it! Let it go!
放手
Let it go!
放  手
Let it...go!
你  给我等着
You are in big trouble.
喂
Yeah.
等等等  慢点说
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
慢
Just sl--
慢着点  从头开始
Slow down. Start from the--
你
You--
你在哪里
You're where?
你他娘...
Why the f--
你干什么
Why are you--
你老毛病又犯了  是不是
Are you seriously doing this to me again?
老天
Jesus, just st--
你别哭行吗
Would you stop crying?
我去找人解决  别乱动
I'll make a phone call. Just sit tight.
你在哪里被抓的
Where do they got you?
好消息  警官和房主谈过了
So good news. The officer spoke to the homeowners,
他们不会提起诉讼
and they're not going to press charges.
很好  那我也不会
Good. I won't, either.
好的  那么  我们走吧
Okay, then, so we're good to go.
走吗
You ready?
玛丽  你想回家吗
Marie, you want to go home?
玛丽
Marie?
(索尔・古德曼 ，律师)
(SAUL GOODMAN,ATTORNEY AT LAW)
你好  我是斯凯勒・怀特
Yes, it's Skyler White
找索尔・古德曼  谢谢
calling for Saul Goodman, please.
对  事关重大
Yes, it is important.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉  结果一样
Sorry. Same as before.
但这样不行啊
But this is not right.
你不能让我关门  不能这样
You cannot shut me down. You cannot do this.
沃利兹先生  我由里至外地检测了您的污水
Mr. Wolynetz, I've checked your waste water inside and out.
也检测了排水沟
I've checked your runoff gutters,
但这里的污染物含量更高
and now out here more contaminants--
有氨  丙酮
ammonia, acetone,
苯和硝基苯
benzene, nitrobenzene.
不不不  肯定是误会
No, no, no. This is a mistake.
加里人呢  他会告诉你
Where is Gary? He will tell you
我的肥皂很好  很环保
my soap is very good, very green.
不  不是你肥皂的问题
No, your soap is not the issue.
而是你过滤系统的问题
It's your filtration system.
最起码  你得更新一下
At the very least, you'll need to retrofit.
但如果你的污水将渗入地下水中
But if you're leeching into the ground water,
就此地看来是非常有可能的
which is looking like a real possibility here,
你就需要替换整个系统
you're going to need to replace your system entirely.
替换  你知道那要花多少钱吗
Replace? Do you know how much cost that is?
二十万
$200,000.
我知道这是道坎
Look, I understand it's a hardship.
我们也可以给你一份核准供应商名单
If you like, we can give you a list of approved vendors.
你要是准备着手更换
If you get going immediately,
请务必在四至五周内完成
your down time shouldn't be any more than four or five weeks.
好吧  抱歉  你说得对
Okay. So sorry. You're right.
即刻起  我们会加倍小心
From now on, we will be extra careful
减少污水排放
and, uh, clean.
停止污染  行吗
No more pollution, okay?
-可以了吗  -抱歉
- Yes? - No, I'm sorry.
目前的状况需要你暂停所有商业活动
The state requires you to suspend all commercial activity
直至此污染等级降低至最低标准
until these levels reach the mandated minimums.
那个加里人呢
Where is usual man? Where is Gary?
他被调配去拉斯克鲁塞斯了
He got transferred to Las Cruces.
如果你想申诉  可以联系...
If you'd like to file an appeal, you can contact--
我什么都没做错
I have done nothing wrong.
告诉我啊  为什么要我停止营业
Tell me, why you shut me down?
我犯了什么法
What laws did I break?
什么法  好几个呢
What laws? Several.
告诉我哪个法哪一条  不然我不接受
Tell me exact specific laws, or I refuse.
-要听具体的吗  -快说
- Specific? - Right now.
那个...
The--
给我说清楚
Tell me exact--
-具体是...  -快说
- The specific laws... - What laws?
等等
Hold on, okay?
别急  别急
Hold on. Hold on.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
好了好了
Okay. Okay.
根据1978年《新墨西哥有害废弃物控制法案》
The New Mexico Hazardous Waste Act of 1978,
第三部分  第四章
Section 74, Chapter 4,
第74条  无论何时发生固体有害废弃物的
Part 13 states, "Whenever the disposal of solid waste
废料处理
or hazardous waste presents--"
造成或可能造成巨大危害的
...an imminent or substantial endangerment,
在污染发生期间  可对违法者
the offender may be fined not more than $5,000 each day
每天最多处以五千美元的罚款
in which the violation occurs.
好了
All right. Okay.
还有
Now the...
宝贝乖
Okay, baby.
有了  美国环保署能根据
All right. The EPA can cite him
1976年颁布的《有毒物品控制法》
under the Toxic Substances--
《美国法典》第十五篇
...Control Act of 1976,
第五十三章
U.S. Code Title 15,
第一节
Chapter 53--
第2606条
Subchapter 1--
对你进行传讯
...Section 2606.
满意了吗
Satisfied?
你觉得
Was that specific--
够具体了吗
...enough for you?
午饭吃了吗
All done with lunch?
吃了
Hmm.
你根本什么都没吃
You hardly touched this.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
把这白米布丁给吃了
I'm leaving the rice pudding.
我不饿  玛丽
I'm not hungry, Marie.
那就别吃
So don't eat it.
你好啊  玛丽
Hey, Marie. How you doing?
我很好  有什么事吗
I-- I'm okay. Is there a problem?
没有  没事
No, no. Everything's fine.
我是来看汉克的
I'm here for Hank, actually.
你人真好
Oh. You're so sweet.
汉克一定会很高兴
Hank will be thrilled.
亲爱的  有人来看你了
Sweetie, you have a visitor.
天呐  又怎么了
Ah, Jesus. What now?
她抢银行了吗
She rob a bank?
老兄  最近好点了吗
Hey, buddy. How you doing?
能有什么怨言
Oh, well, can't complain, you know.
每天都好一点
Every day a little better.
那很好  你看上去气色不错
That's good. You're looking good.
谁让哥天生丽质呢
Yeah, well, handsome was never the hard part.
快进来坐
Come on in. Grab a seat.
东西随便扔哪里
Yeah, just throw that stuff anywhere.
听着
Listen, uh...
再次为那天的事感谢你
thanks again for the other day.
这整件事
You know, this-- this whole thing,
对她来说  很难接受
it's, uh, it's been hard on her.
不用谢  小事一桩
Forget it. Glad to help.
看来你在收集石头
So, rock collecting?
这些是矿石
They're minerals. Yeah.
实际上我在做目录
Uh, it's cataloging them--
分类  再加个标记
sort them, label them.
可够我忙的
Um, it's actually a lot of work.
是吗  看上去是的
Yeah? No, it looks like it.
找我什么事
So, what's up?
实际上  我是来找你帮忙的
Well, actually, I could use your help on something.
谋杀案  有可能还和毒品有关
Homicide, possibly drug-related.
你想让我跟进这个案子
You want my help on the case?
你当我是铁人吗
What am I, Ironside?
不  可你是个缉毒警察  熟悉本地的行家
No. But you're a drug cop who knows the local talent,
而且我还帮过你一个忙
and you're a pal I just did a favor for,
所以就让我占用你几分钟时间
so let me pick your brain a second.
你对一个名叫
You ever come across a guy
盖尔・伯蒂彻有印象吗
by the name of Gale Boetticher?
没有
No.
有人朝他脸上射了一枪
Someone came along and shot him in the face.
然后呢
Okay.
没有强行进入的迹象
No signs of forced entry,
也不像是抢劫案
no signs of robbery.
这只是冲动犯罪
Okay, so it's a crime of passion.
和毒品有什么关系
Where's the drug angle?
我们在他房间发现了一本笔记本
We found a notebook at his place.
我觉得你会感兴趣  就为你复印了一份
I made a copy for you in case you're interested.
它看上去和制作甲基苯丙胺的实验室有关
Looks like it pertains to some kind of methamphetamine superlab.
这上面都是些科学公式
It's filled with scientific formulas
和化学药品清单及图案
and chemical purchase lists... drawings,
整页整页都是这些东西
pages and pages of this stuff.
这事肯定不简单  可我又不是行家
It looks big time, but I'm no authority,
所以来问你是否愿意看一下
so I wonder if you might take a look.
得了吧  提姆  说真的
Come on, Tim, seriously.
这算什么  对我的一种施舍
What is this, some kind of a charity thing?
我认为你的专家意见会有帮助
I thought your expertise could be useful here.
我现在躺着就像在三垒上
I'm lying here like, uh, third base,
每天的事情就是吃喝拉撒
living from bowel movement to bowel movement.
我自己都觉得我很没用
I'm not even useful to myself.
想问我的意见
Want my advice?
把它给史蒂芬・戈麦斯
Take this to Steve Gomez.
他会帮你的
He'll help you out.
要是我把这给史蒂芬・戈麦斯
I give this to Steve Gomez,
这就会变成毒品管制局的案子
and all of a sudden it becomes a DEA case.
这对我又有什么好处
What good does that do me?
要是你能看一眼
If you could just take a look,
告诉我这是什么
tell me what I got here,
我会十分感激的
I'd really appreciate it.
好吧
Whatever.
多谢了  老兄
Thanks, man.
慢慢来
You take it easy.
我还能干什么
That's what I do.
你那方法是不错
Well, it was a good try.
好啦  该睡觉觉咯
Here we go. Time for your nap. Yeah.
你真乖
Oh, you're great.
这么说
So...
美甲店还是比较靠谱的
Nail Salon sounded promising.
你觉得怎样
What do you think?
我觉得我们应该等等
I think we wait.
等等
Wait.
斯凯勒  都已经5个小时了
Skyler, it has been five hours.
他会打来的
He'll call.
等等吧
Ahem. Just wait.
Just wait.
听着
Look.
这是个好办法  不错的主意
It was a good idea. It was a great idea.
可没作用
But it didn't work.
我们就当是吸取了一次教训
So why don't we simply chalk it up as a learning--
这里是怀特家
White residence.
你好啊  沃利兹先生
Oh, hello, Mr. Wolynetz.
问我还有兴趣吗
Am I still interested?
那就得看情况了
Well, I-- I think that depends.
是的  87.9万美元是最初的报价
Yes, 879 was the original offer,
可现在我觉得贵了
but that seems high to me now.
我现在出价80万
Now I'm offering 800.
别  别  别  别这样
No, no, no. No, no. Don't do that.
-想知道原因  -别这样
- Why? - Don't do that.
因为你是一个令人讨厌的人  沃利兹先生
Well, because you're an unpleasant person, Mr. Wolynetz.
你非但对我不敬  还不尊重我的丈夫
You were rude to me and disrespectful towards my husband.
-斯凯勒  -还有就是
- Skyler-- - And furthermore,
我已经见过其他卖家了
I've met with quite a number of sellers,
这市场比我想象的要疲软许多
and the market seems much softer than I thought.
所以我报价80万
So 800.
你真是一派胡言  80万
You are talking crazy. 800?
你真是一个疯女人
You are a very, very crazy lady.
我知道你很失望
Well, I understand that you're disappointed,
可这是我的最后价位
but that is my final offer.
很遗憾我们没能做成交易
I'm sorry we couldn't make it work.
再见
Goodbye.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我在谈判
I'm negotiating.
为什么这么做
Why?
因为我想花得少一点
Because I want to pay less.
便宜7.9万
$79,000 less?
就为这点小钱  你知道我现在一天赚多少
Who cares? Do you know how much I make in a day?
知道  所以我们才要谈判
Yeah, but that's the very reason we need to negotiate.
我们不希望因为我们
We don't want to arouse suspicion
没有讨价还价而引起猜疑
by not trying to get a good deal.
听着  我懂你的想法
Look, I get the logic. I do.
可你有点过分了
But you just went too far with it.
你居然骂他
You're calling him names?
我可没骂他
I didn't call him names.
我只是说他很无理
I said he was unpleasant.
他不会回你电话了
Well, he's not calling you back.
你不会真以为这会成功吧
I mean, you didn't honestly think that worked.
没错
Yeah, I do.
这下彻底没戏了
No way. Sorry. No.
该想想别的主意了  好吗
It's time to move on, ok?
我这就给索尔打电话
I'm going to call Saul.
我的电话呢
Where's my phone?
别接
No.
-为什么  -先别接
- What?  - No, just...
-还等什么
- What for?
等等  等等
Wait, wait.
等什么
For--
我的老天爷
Oh, my God.
您好
Hello.
您好  沃利兹先生
Hello, Mr. Wolynetz.
没人真正关心这些东西在哪里
No one's really paying attention to where these things are.
它们遍布世界各地  到处都是
I mean, there's got to be thousands of them all over the world
被装上渔船  朝咱们开来
and on boats coming right for us.
之后放进巨大的冷冻车上
And put on inside an ice cream truck,
开到旧金山
drive it into San Francisco.
我一点都不害怕被食人鱼吃掉
I'm not even that scared of burning up in cannibalism.
对于我来说  我只是担心
To me the things that-- thing that worries me
被蹂躏
is-- is getting trampled
或在铁丝网上被挤来挤去
or-- or shoved up against a chain link fence
因为你如果真的仔细想想的话
because if you really think about it,
如果你真的被压在铁丝网上挤来挤去
if you were against a chain link fence
你肯定会
and you've got a-- a lot--
我是说肯定有很多人想要逃离
I mean a lot of people trying to escape,
他们就会拼命向前推搡
pushing hard enough forward.
这不是开玩笑  你会被人挤穿过
It's not a joke. You're going to get squeezed
那道铁丝网
right through the chain links
就像华润或其它肉类
like Pla-Doh or some kind of soft meat.
这是不可避免的
Uh, and this is inevitable, okay?
这是你或我或任何人都无法阻止的
And there's nothing you or me or anyone can do about it.
如果这个铁丝网柱被死死地
And if the fence posts are stuck deep--
卡在水泥最深处
really deep with the cement way down inside the ground,
这种事绝对会发生的
then it's definitely happening to you.
就像墙上的血
Blood on the wall.
中了
Yeah. Bitch.
有人被杀了  肯定有人被杀了
Somebody got shot. Somebody probably got shot.
就像那些肉
Like soft meat, man,
就像那些
right through--
被铁丝网挤穿的肉
being squeezed through there like soft meat.
就像那些被铁丝网挤穿的肉
Like soft meat, right through the chain.
被铁丝网挤穿
Right through the-- Right through the chain.
无可避免
It's-- It's inevitable. Just--
来钱啦
Money!
太好了
Ohh, nice.
敬
To...
洗车和洗钱
clean cars and clean money.
干杯
Hear, hear.
我说什么来着
You see?
咱们能买到这个洗车场
I told you we'd get it.
是吗
Did you?
说真的  你这仗干得可真漂亮
Seriously, that was really great work.
佩服
It's impressive.
谢谢
Thank you.
索尔也帮了点小忙
And Saul finally came through.
他找了那个人
Well, I mean, he found the guy, right?
是啊  他找了那个人
Well, yes, he found the guy,
但每步都是我给的指示
but I told him what to do and what to say.
对 你说的对  这才是最难的地方
You're right. That's the hard part.
但是索尔也挺有用
But yes, Saul was, uh... finally useful.
得给他点奖励
Throw him a bone.
天呐
Oh, my God.
这酒真的很好喝
This is truly amazing.
这瓶最起码得值320美元
Yes, well, it better be at $320 a bottle.
什么
What?
波尔罗杰牌  维斯顿・丘吉尔先生香槟
Cuvee Pol Roget Sir Winston Churchill.
很明显是他最爱的香槟酒
Apparently, it was his favorite champagne,
所以他们以他的名字命名
so they just named it after him.
你是如何支付的
How did you pay for it?
我不明白你的意思
What do you mean?
现金  我付现金
Ah. No. Cash. I paid cash.
不是  我是在问你沃尔特・怀特
No, I'm-- I'm asking how did you, Walter White,
一名失业的前中学教师如何能买得起
an unemployed schoolteacher, pay for it?
你该怎样解释
How do you explain it?
斯凯勒  我买的时候没人看到我
Skyler, no one saw me.
卖给你的人绝对看到了  但这不是重点
Whoever sold it to you did, and that's not the point.
重点是我们破产了  记得吗
The point is we're broke, remember?
我是指  我还在等你的失业救济支票
I mean, I'm waiting for your unemployment check to come
来支付电话费
so I can pay the phone bill.
我要求电力公司延长我们的交款期
I asked for an extension from the power company.
为啥  因为严格意义上讲  我们没钱
Why? Because on paper, we have no money.
你多虑了
You are completely overreacting.
我不会为用微不足道的方式庆祝而道歉
I'm not apologizing for wanting to celebrate in some small way.
我不是要求你道歉  沃尔特
I'm not asking you to apologize, Walt.
我是要求你变得聪明点
I'm asking you to be smart.
我就买了一瓶香槟
I bought one bottle of champagne,
就一瓶  斯凯勒
one single bottle, Skyler.
我付了现金  仅此而已
I paid cash. That's it.
也只能就此打住
That's all it takes, okay?
想想水门事件吧
I mean, look at Watergate.
就那么一小块胶带
One... One little piece of duct tape
-留在门上   -我的天呐
-left in a door  -Oh, my G--.
把美国总统拉下马
...brought down the President of the United States.
什么  我成尼克松了吗
What, I'm Nixon now?
不是  我的意思是
No, what I'm saying is
细节决定成败
the devil is in the details, okay?
只要我们的故事里有一点点疏漏
One little mistake, one slip-up in our story,
都会把我们俩毁了的
that could ruin us.
好吧
Fine.
得赶紧把证据消灭掉
Got to destroy the evidence.
每次当我看到眼前这个画面
When I look at this-- this image
这份档案的一部分
that is part of the record,
我很担心这对于我们来说
I am very concerned about what sort of distraction
将是多大的干扰
that can be,
不管是怎样的标识
whether it's from any sort of signage
尤其是这样每五秒钟更换一次的标识
but especially a signage that's changing every five seconds.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有其它问题吗
Any other questions?
在这级第二个位置有个请求
We have a motion and a second on the floor
同意此项上诉
to grant the appeal.
同意者请举手并示意同意
All those in favor, raise your hand and say yes.
示意同意即为肯定
Yes is for the affirmative.
反对者
Those opposed?
已经有五位提出反对意见  上诉失败
There's five no's, and that motion fails.
在此我想为此教育广播公司及卢波公司的
I would like to make a motion to uphold the decision
调查与决定提出支持议案
and the findings of the EBC and the Lupo.
议案以及副案由库克议员提出
We have a motion and a second
有什么问题
by Councilor Cooke. Any questions?
没有  所有人都同意
I see none. All those in favor,
此全员同意意味着否定上诉
signify by saying yes to deny the appeal.
同意者请举手并示意同意
All those in favor, signify by saying yes.
五人同意
That's five in the affirmative.
反对者请举手并示意反对
All those opposed, say no.
四人反对
There's four in the negative.
此议案通过
That passes.